So the market's trading, yeah, it's relatively stable, and then an order comes in from a biser client, it's a firm, it's a corporation, let's say, it's a business, 50 million long, that, let's say, pushes price out into this threshold, into this state of liquidity where sellers start to draw away from price, right?
that condition alone can persist for minutes, hours, days, weeks
and that doesn't even have to reflect the sentiment regarding new downline currency.
So let's say it's GDP, UST.
We know right now there's no real effort in the market
or willingness in the market to buy the pound up massively
without worrying about Brexit.
There's a lot of uncertainty, yeah?
Yeah.
But we still get huge, huge moves to the upside.
Yes, there's an element of speculative flows, speculative flows,
and there are people bidding it up, taking positions.
But the point I'm making here is a volume shot at the right time
can push price into a condition where then the sale of liquidity continues like that.
The price stays in that price run for a while.
Overbuy's comment, obviously, there'll be people's buy stops getting hit.
This price run doesn't necessarily have to reflect the true.
underlying value of GbPUSD, right? It could take on short-term moves, which move away from the
general direction or the larger trend. If it pushes past the right threshold, so this is like
that threshold, but there's a bit of cell weakness. As and when price starts to push past it,
it goes into that condition of sell weakness, buy liquidity is pushing along with price, buy volume
is then the sell side is more sensitive to buy volume, and price can continue in that direction
for minutes, dozens of minutes, hours, days, do you get it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So people, obviously, a lot of the time people take on this idea or subscribe to the idea
that all these price runs are manufactured or price moves are manufactured to trick you, right?
Or that there's even entities out there that are trying to take your money, etc.
It's just a fallacy.
This price run is just a function of market dynamics we're discussing quite thoroughly.
but the point I'm really making is the right volume at the right time can trigger a price response
and it can push price into a state of liquidity where it just travels in that direction
because it's the path of least resistance for that day right and we saw that actually
happened on cable yesterday yeah I'll just show you we had a highly highly inefficient price run
this was after a headline the headline it was you know how we've had this issue of Brexit talks
yeah France Prime Minister came out and said he's willing to concede on some hard
lines so Europe is basically saying the European negotiators basically showing signs of
you know they're willing to compromise yeah which is likely a sign that they want to talk with
the UK and eventually reach a deal rather than telling them to fuck off so we had this headline
price popped the fuck out it went absolutely berserk here and after that what am I
talking about sorry bro is here it went absolutely berserk there
There was a headline that day as well, but I'm talking about Friday.
So it went berserk, it popped out, it was quite a big move, 44 pips within five minutes.
And then because of how inefficient it was, it left behind that void of liquidity.
As the volume dried off up there, no bidders came in here all day.
Yeah.
You get it.
For the rest of the day, price just drifted lower and lower and lower and lower until it reached here and it hit people's sell stops.
so if you had a long buy position here
your stop loss is a sell
order yeah yeah
a sell stop
once cell stops get triggered
they turn into market orders
so here we saw heavy market order selling
and I'll like a buy liquidity anyway
so the point of making this move doesn't reflect
strength it doesn't reflect anything
over than just
it's a price run as a function of liquidity
we know the the characteristics
of liquidity it's not constant
it's always changing so they could be 1 million here
There could be $50 million there.
There could be nothing here.
It's also dynamic.
So there could be $50 million here, but it disappears.
People remove it.
I mean, the same applies with cell volume as well, or any volume as well.
Because of these dynamics, we have conditions created where you have areas or price
runs, which are moving on low volume just to the weaker direction.
It's not because there's a huge seller there.
We have these type of price moves, the one that popped out.
it's like a compounded
extreme version of what's going on here
with more driving force
we had the headline, sellers disappeared
almost instantaneously
the buy volume which is buying pound up
is reacting to the positive news
drove price higher
seeking sell liquidity which is just not present
and we saw a heavy heavy heavy
highly volatile move
volatility is a function of available liquidity
there was hardly any sell liquidity here
And price just, you know, it cut through it like a fucking knife.
Imagine there's no air there, right?
It's like an air pocket.
A pocket, you know, if there's an air pocket, you know,
if there was an air pocket in your room right now,
all that, you know, the atmospheric pressure would gush into there.
The air would push into that pocket where there's no, so, aka a vacuum.
So yeah, these are the points I'm ready making.
All these price runs don't reflect anything.
there are times like this right on Wednesday there was a massive fucking
buyer in the market on Wednesday a huge huge huge huge buy on on on Wednesday it would
likely have been one or two firms filling a huge order 200 million 300 million
over the course of that day which then is happening alongside the normal
business of the day as well so you have other business going on you might have
had a corporation selling the pound, buying the dollar for whatever reason, for whatever
logistical reasons. You might have had no selling here, but another firm buying pound here
because they need to, you know, it could have been a hedge fund that's hedging some risk.
It could have been a pension fund that needs to just hedge some risk in a pound.
Yeah. Any number of reasons, yeah. That is continuing. The normal business is happening.
once there's a huge huge bidder
you get it
yeah
these are the characteristics you still typically see
in those large directional moves
biobases hold
they don't stop holding
it's relentless
this is like the aggressive
midflow kind of thing isn't it
yeah it's highly inefficient midflow
so what we're looking at here
is the midflow characteristics
are reflecting the state of liquidity
the state of liquidity was that there's
thick bids moving higher quite aggressively
and obviously sell weakness
we know that
but overall
if we had to describe this move
it would be classed as inefficient
because there was heavy
let's just say there was 200 million
that wants to get brought here
there wasn't 200 million
sell liquidity there to match it with
it had to spread
this 200 million had to get spent
to small pieces
and get matched out
over a distance of prices
meaning each level
wasn't traded that thickly
there wasn't a huge buildup of buyers
so
the midfair characteristics they reflect the state of liquidity the state of liquidity here is heavy
in balance yeah there's heavy heavy heavy buying thick thick buy liquidity and relatively weaker in comparison
some liquidity but it's kind of important that you can connect with the significance of what
I'm saying when I say that these did like this price move here doesn't mean shit that price
run up doesn't really mean shit it could just be one order from a random entity at the right time
initially pushing price out
and as price pushed out
for the short term
you know immediate period
after that the cell
weakness all throughout this period
all throughout this area there's no cell
or lack of cell liquidity left over in that area
just that volume shot there
volume comes out the right time
price pushes out
cell liquidity dissipates and disappears
disperses and one second
all go
sorry about that
that's all right
So yeah
Price runs on price movements
Do not necessarily reflect sentiment
Actually what you'll find in the FX market
If there is a large large
You know directional move
Or a directional bias in a market
From speculative entities
Who take on positions because they expect the pound
Is pound is overvalued
So they want to push it lower
They expect pound to go to this true value
Which is at lower price over the next 5, 10, 2, 3 years
They
Them speculative traders
are not aggressive typically, right?
The way they trade is by the price-sensitive traders
they want to build positions in, let's say, certain areas,
they'll build a huge short position consistently over time,
not constantly.
So they're not selling, selling, selling, selling,
because they're bearish on the pound.
Rather, they're building a big position
and they then turn into large, large, large liquidity providers.
They're consistently providing liquidity,
huge amounts of sell liquidity, huge amounts of sell liquidity,
at these levels. As you can see here, there's huge, huge cell positions being built up.
Every time price came up, they snatched it up, absorbed the buying, absorb the buying, absorb the buying, absorb the buying, time and time again.
Right. So, yeah, large speculative traders, they're more passive in these NFX markets. They're not active, aggressive force like you'd get in SEP 500 or Dow Jones.
And the effect of that is, over the long run, if there is a trend, they won't be.
aggressively pushing price down so as and when price draws out it dries off any to find the cell
liquidity again the path of fees resistance will be right back up to find the sellers to build
the sellers will build up here and then you get your next trend move you follow me yeah yeah well
if it was aggressive it just continued down in a straight man wouldn't it yeah that sell liquidity
you would move down and then it would move down and then it would move down and it would continue
to happen now most of these moves here that's brexit
this was the US dollar going crazy basically because they thought the interest rates were going to rise in the US this is coronavirus so any of these large and fast moves you'll see and they're not they're not usual moves they're not natural moves they're always event driven sentiment changing you know there was an event that affected the sentiment for a short period of time and price just goes crazy over then those periods it's stay
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's almost always stable. Don't get it twisted. There are huge positions being built here. There is a very, very, very large buyer building a position here. But they building it passively through limit orders, not aggressively market order driving price. They're price sensitive, yeah? Who the fuck wants to try to get filled for $2 billion over the next two, three days through market orders? You don't think liquidity providers will spot the pattern of market order buying these.
think they'll be providing sell liquidity if there's a huge market owner buyer
consistently bidding up the pound for the next 48 hours they have to try higher the information
if you are an entity that needs to get filled for 2 billion and you because you expect the
pound is undervalued there's a whole like there's a whole research field called transactional
cost analysis and the purpose of this is to identify the trading costs of trading through
certain types of ways. So the simplest
like form of analysis that they could do is
if you want to get filled for a big position,
what is the cost of it doing it through market orders
versus limit orders?
Another example of this could be
how costly is it to try
get filled for $2 billion with one
liquidity provider compared
with five? So if I split this $2 billion
across five liquidity providers.
And these are very simplistic, you know, controlled kind of experiments they can do.
There's very, very, you know, as a by-side firm, you can curate your own liquidity pool
consisting of various different types of liquidity providers.
And then you can instruct those liquidity providers to give you different types of liquidity.
So there's like, on one hand, you could have a liquidity provider that's consistently updating their prices.
So there's streaming prices to you that you can trade on.
Another one could be where they are giving.
you prices for a big amount.
So if you want to get filled for $50 million,
you can request that one quote
from one liquidity provider.
You will decide if they want to give that.
You know, so on streaming prices,
if I'm an LP streaming prices,
here's my best bid, best offer.
I'm buying expensive, selling cheap.
I'm not going to put a huge amount of liquidity there.
I might only offer $1 million at each level.
But if I go for a, you know,
if a client comes to me as a, I'm a liquidity provider,
If a client comes to me and they want a full amount to feed or a full amount to price feed,
I might give them a slightly wider spread, but with 20 million behind it.
Okay.
Because then they can, you know, they're asking for that large feed.
They're asking for that large quote with large liquidity behind it where they will trade directly with me.
So LPs can like, you know, they can provide different types of liquidity depending on the client,
et cetera, et cetera.
So large buyside clients, the point of everything I'm saying, the large byside clients,
their whole purpose is they're trying to make money if you're a speculative trader.
You're trying to make money in the market.
You want to get filled for a huge amount.
But the problem is trading under a certain style through market orders, sorry,
through market orders might result in 0.4% extra high execution costs.
If I trade through here, it might result in 0.4%.
percent saving costs.
0.4% of $2 billion is a huge amount.
Yeah.
You get it.
That drives their, you know, if they're trying to make profit,
saving on costs is a form of increasing your profit.
So a whole research field is out of there,
transactional cost analysis where they inspect the different types of liquidity
pools that you can trade with the different methods of transactions.
That's how execution algorithms came about.
Because these firms, they wanted to hide their information
once they're trying to get filled for large amounts of large,
large notional amounts of water flow.
So they need these kind of execution
outgoes to facilitate
finding them liquidity without causing too much market impact,
aka hiding information leakage.
They don't want anybody else to know that there's a
$2 billion being brought.
If I said to you tomorrow on Monday night
that here is $2 billion buyer,
you might be okay with buying it here
and just putting your stop down there.
you might, you know, aggressively start to buy
before that $2 billion buyer gets to get filled.
Anticipating that buyer is going to continue to buy as well.
Imagine everybody did that.
So everybody was aware there's a large buyer there.
Yeah.
Everybody buys here, a price runs up.
This guy who's trying to get filled for $2 billion has to accept a higher price now.
Yeah.
Why?
Because information about his order was leaked.
Everybody else became aware of it.
So all these kind of dynamics, you know, all this stuff exists.
So TCA is a huge, there's a huge effort.
around it so did you get a chance to go over the chart and find those parabolic um to be honest
with you i did it just on my phone you know you know that's fine yeah i just did it on my phone um
they're they're visible everywhere that's the thing yeah they're they're they're happy all the
spot as well so price swing is composed of two price runs yeah a to be back to a yeah
why is the price swing form it because the state of liquidity is changing yeah so you have market order buying thick by liquidity relatively thin as sell liquidity and price pushes out here you'll see the imbalance characteristic midflow yeah then when that midflow we start to show the intensity of buying is slowing down there's bi liquidity weakness we see a change in that characteristic and then we tend to see that parabolic phase which is kind of draining the available liquidity in this area and simultaneously
as a result of that volatility
you typically see a lack of willingness to buy
anyway. Whenever you
get high volatility periods
like this
even that
that day there
that what does price
do immediately after
it just dries up into nothing.
Price just dries up
right after high volatility periods
there's definitely loads of buying going on
doing the high volatility periods
loads of volume
volume wanting to transact, a lack of sell liquidity there. Surprise pushes out, becomes super
aggressive. It's like a climax. Think of it as a climax. The volume's climax. If we're
looking at a chart of how much volume is trading, here's a natural volume we trade in. And then in
the parabolic phase, it's rising quite aggressively. And after that, the volume just doesn't
come back in for a while. The volume just dies off. Do you get it? So here's the normal volume
trading here's the parabolic phase and then after the volume just climb up it takes a cliff
dive again variable volume flow it's like taking uh highly caffeinated the things like you you
feel good for a certain amount of time and then when it dries then when like it dries off
yeah yeah and then like you just feel shit yeah yeah yeah look man these this kind of you know
the willingness to buy it more and more expensive prices on the fast conditions it's like
a human nature thing. Nobody wants to, who the fuck wants to do that? It's costly to trade under
highly volatile conditions. So I'm trying to buy. There's no sell liquidity there. I'm having to
accept more and more expensive prices to get that liquidity. You can just imagine, if you're
trying to be a buyer here, there has to be a level of irrational. You know, you have to be
somewhat irrational to continue to buy, buy, buy, buy higher and higher prices. Yeah, definitely.
I agree. Right. There is also an elasticity point.
as well. So if price does push
far enough initially
in a highly
volatile way,
buyers can continue to come in
even after the volatility is dried off
and the sell liquidity can stay dispersed.
We'll discuss that.
It's called macrovolatility, basically.
You have these instances
like this, like that
where you would have had high, high
amounts of volatility in the first few days.
And then after that, because
of the event as well,
the event's creating uncertainty
and then the volatility is confirming
it's kind of confirming the event
the willingness to buy here, the buy liquidity
that would normally turn up at these levels
just doesn't turn up.
So you have this huge, huge area of weakness that's created
and still volume continues to come in
at lower and lower and lower prices.
This is irrational.
So yeah, it's a human age kind of thing.
All right.
So in terms of parabolic,
all of these apexes,
It doesn't matter which one I look at, prices typically stable you on the midflow,
and then towards the end, it becomes quite jumpy.
Here, it wasn't all that inefficient.
It started to dry off, draw back in, and then it would have popped.
If you look at it on a more granular scale, it'll become evident to you.
So again, something like this needs validated.
So look, we had relatively stable.
It's definitely inefficient.
It's definitely trading thinly.
There's not a lot of some liquidity there matching with the market order buys,
but price continued to run.
it had a first break of midflow there
continues to run, continues to run
decisive break
and then it goes bam
now look at this candle
yeah so price runs
runs runs runs
it gets thinner and thinner
and thinner the further it runs
now immediately the next candle
start trading back inside of it
think about it if there was buy liquidity here
then the candle
any selling the market would have
opened the next candle would have opened
wherever there was by liquidity
but the immediate bid price
which is this is what this is showing
the immediate bid price
was down there
yeah it already shows them
the buyers aren't even there right now
that's that's
you know a visualization of exhaustion
it was so so so inefficient up there
the next price that buyers were willing to buy at
even it was very thin
it wouldn't have been a lot of buy liquidity
but the next
and first price the buy liquidity turned up
right back down here.
Yeah, immediately lower.
But yeah, so after that, there's a lack of willingness to buy it here,
lack of willingness to market kind of stabilizer, stabilizes.
You're seeing a bit of selling here,
but you can see here there's not that much aggressive selling.
There's not that much aggressive selling.
As soon as it pushes through the last inventory that pushed it to new highs,
the buy liquidity disappears.
If there was any willingness to buy it here,
there's only residual liquidity left, basically.
Yeah, in the mid-price room here.
Right, residual liquidity left.
price draws right back down to core
and this is where you have the first
biggest response
I'm not talking reversal
you just have your biggest response back down at the origin
aka core of this fractal price room
actually responds off it numerous times
and the same kind of dynamic occurs
with this larger swing
you have this as the residual
this is the core
price does respond
relatively you know
it's relatively smaller compared to the size
of the response back down at the core
of the big price swing. So look
each of these moves, they just fill
back up into the last dealing range,
aka inventory, fills back up to
the last dealing range. Time, time again.
That should get a bit more narrower here.
But as it pushes down
into the core, you see your biggest response.
So in that sense, the behaviour is fractal
as well. You have
this price swing,
weak by response, weak by response,
weak by response, all off residual
liquidity. It reaches
back down to the core and you have your biggest
response. The same is
happening here with a big
price swing, relatively weak by
a response, relatively in comparison
to this, weak by a response
weak, weak,
drawback down to core
pretty big.
So in that sense, the behaviours
repeat and the show patterns of self
similarity, not only in how
price moves, but also the behaviours as well.
That end up being
the lower the day.
Yeah, this motherfucker missed me, bro.
I pissed me off.
How many pips did they miss you?
About four, about four pips, three, three. three pips.
So you can see here again, it's more granular,
prices stable, stable, and then surge.
I'm just trying to validate that at your exhaustion,
you can just see there was definitely an event here.
Prices are doing low volume state, low liquid state,
a lack of market order,
lack of market order sales and buys.
event
sell liquidity
is just gone
bro
disappeared
that's mad
that's actually mad
you can see
the dealing range
that it's in
and then like
sold
liquidity just
disappeared
and then
you should
bam
the sell liquidity
disappeared
simultaneously
buying
yeah
that's mad
but here
you have
some
fractal
version of
exhaustion
right
each of these
you know
local
fractal highs
but then there's you there's it's not always this it's not i'll be clear with you it's not always
easy to see and nor is it always as nice as these ones right these two are really really nice
examples and variations of exhaustion parabolic phase sometimes you have less clear ones
but still the ticking here would have been quite quite distinct um what i want to see is
if my level's here for example prices coming up into it is broken
midflow. I want to see it reach for it. I want to see it reach, yeah. What I don't want to see
is price build up into my level. Take one swipe and build up, build up, build up. This is less
favorable. Doesn't mean I won't take that trade there. I will sometimes, but I'll be managing
a much more closely. And it's much, psychologically at least, it's a bit harder to sit in these
trades, right? Because what I'm relying on here is a combination of sell limit order strength
and by weakness, right, for this trade to work. Here, I don't really need sell order,
selling order strength, bro. I don't really need it. This is so, so inefficient and weak.
And I'm deciphering, you know, I'm identifying that is so weak because of the ticking.
We can see it in the ticking in the way the candle forms. Here, you need less things to go your
way for price to respond.
In both these instances, they're both
valid trades. This is
just more favourable compared to this one
and you never know which one's
going to occur because you can't until the future.
So when you take a trade or when you're
looking at a level and identifying how price
is moving in towards it, you actually don't
know exactly
how it will form, but you can anticipate for sure.
Over time, you'll experience
this, many, many, many times. You'll experience this, many, many times
as well, over the course
of thousands of
experiences, you will be able
to identify this as it's happening
quickly.
Okay.
Right?
So, I'm trying to think of an analogy
when you spot something.
I can't take bit now.
But there's this kind of thing in your brain,
RAS or something.
The whole purpose of it is to be able
to spot things in patterns.
Right?
And the more you experience price,
the more you go over price
and a detailed way tracking it, observing it,
rather than trying to trade it,
you'll be burning the characteristics of price behaviours
which are favourable into your psyche.
Over time, you'll be able to identify the nature of moves
which are more favourable to trade,
the nature of moves which are less favourable to trade.
Even if both have valid expectancy,
i.e., both of these will win money over time.
This is much more likely to.
went over this one. The shades of this. So, you know, there's a higher probability this works out
compared to this. Even though both have a positive expectancy, I would ideally want all of my
trades to trade on this, you know, I don't know which one's going to occur. There's many different
variations of highs, lows, mid-flows. They can be aggressive, they can be relatively stable.
The parabolic phase can be super, super jumpy and it can reach for your level, or it can actually
be more where there's a lot of sell liquidity absorbing any buying so price pops out and
actually picks up the sell of limit orders at least some of them price makes another attempt
the sell limit orders are absorbing them makes another attempt to make sell limit orders
are absorbing them until the willingness to buy the buy liquidity here is finished yeah the the second
one I don't think that yeah I don't think it'd be nice seeing and if you're seeing price keep on
reaching for that same level again you don't know if it'll break
over time you know you'll build that into your into your like you'll experience it
and because you've experienced it so much you'll identify the characteristic so here
there's going to be variations when this loses right when this trade is likely going to go
to your stop loss there'll be very very distinct differences between the characteristics
of this this trade when it works and it's going to win and when it loses what's required
of you is though to track it throughout its duration you can't just take the trade here and expect it to
work because probabilities can change over time though we will be discussing it quite soon actually
the characteristics of winners of losers both of these the initial high holds it's very simple
but it's this example of what you know this variation is what we're seeing here price made
its final high it makes multiple attempts to draw back in by that point the bi-liquity here is kind of drained
We already broke the flow technically here.
Yeah.
We popped out, came back in, picked up this next small pocket of liquidity.
Grabbed, grabbed, grabbed, grabbed, grabbed it again, grabbed it again, draining the buy liquidity here.
And notice how the buy response has got weaker, failed to push, failed to push.
We're consistently seeing.
If you were to look at this price swing in isolation, actually, this one.
So that's A, that's B.
it failed to make it back to A
If I showed you a price swing that did this
There should be a question in your mind
Like why the fuck this not going back to core
Why did it respond to residual?
Here this is actually responding
Of a residual level of this fractal price swing
Which kind of exemplifies how weak the bids are in this area
Yeah if it was strong
Yeah it would go back at least
Yeah
The characteristics we see here as well
The bioliquity was drained
It was grabbed, grabbed.
So, look, we have this whole area.
We grabbed the top side.
We grabbed the pickup of the top side, fell to move.
We went deeper into the bottom of this area of bi liquidity.
That fell to push successfully.
And this whole area was subsequently drained.
And the same thing happens, I guess, deeper in these levels, is consistently draining.
Why are we seeing?
Can you think of a reason why all the biocally?
liquidity that price is picking up off this area is weak what was that why these price
response is likely weak you know what kind of reason would there be for why the buy liquidity is
fern into push fell into push fell into push where previously it picks up the last buy base runs
picks up the last buy base i hear it didn't but in midflow here's your last range price comes
grabs it moves on comes grabs it moves on comes and grabs it moves on comes and grabs it moves on
When it breaks, it's kind of draining this area.
It's grabbed all the bi-liquidy, and then it pops.
Now, as price comes back in, because this area is drained, we typically see weak response.
It fails to push.
We might see you make another attempt.
Might make another attempt.
It fails to push.
It makes an attempt, fails to push.
Every single time the buyer tried, it failed to push, fell to push, fell to push.
Because all of these lows, wherever they're feeding off,
They're feeding off an area that's weak.
Why is this area weak?
Because it was drained.
Price grabbed it, grabbed it, actually broke mid-flow, deeply tested it, grabbed all the available inventory and pushed it out.
Okay.
Are you following me?
So, yeah, so, so wouldn't here, I know he said liquidity being transferred is wrong.
Yeah.
But does it not seem like it's transferring here?
where um how you said or it picks it up my pick up i mean so uh i'll explain you you said something to do with
the pick up of something else yeah so i'll explain it through uh the amount of limit orders yeah so
here let's just say there's a hundred million price comes and hits that hundred million
is picked them right so let's just say it filled 10 of them than 90 million left 10 million got
picked up yeah that's what i mean so they got filled
Oh, okay. Yeah, you said pick up, but pick up.
Yeah, yeah. So there's 90 million left over.
And then it comes back down again.
No, the 90 million is moving along with price at a certain tempo
because of the way these orders are filled in the market.
Okay.
The transaction of the methods in which large orders are filled,
they don't just weight our prices, they follow along with price.
So if price moves up, they're not going to stay down here.
The likelihood of them being filled down here is almost zero.
The further price moves against it.
so you want to buy it here but the price is moving away from you
you're not going to get filled yeah so what can you do
yeah you'll have to move your you know you have to expect
yeah on an automated basis
you you know as a large trader you've accepted
you're not going to get filled for as much as you want
at your level because there's information leakage
there's some form of information leakage these are extremely like
advanced forms
the way they can decipher information is just ridiculous
prove. They can look at the level
of update, the price frequency updates
from liquidity providers, how they
change across each other. They call the size of
the spreads. If one
dealer is quoting widespread, yeah, so they're
willing to buy competitively,
more to buy
the bids in the market or
relatively the same price, and then
one LP has an ask price up here.
Meaning,
he doesn't want to provide
sell liquidity here, here, here, here.
It's likely because he has some
short exposure already.
I'll put it to you this way, yeah?
So this is one liquidity provider.
He has a bid and the ask here.
And then another liquidity provider has a bid here and the ask there.
They're all relatively the same level.
They're adjusting their bid and asks obviously based on the internal flow.
When a client goes long here with this fourth liquidity provider, the LP now is a short
position.
They probably don't want to take on further shorts until they can trade out.
short position.
Maybe they're waiting for someone to sell to them down here.
So whilst that's happening, they might move their ask price higher.
Now, if you're another client that's sourcing prices from all liquidity providers,
this guy's price is out of market.
You don't really want to buy his price because you could buy at this guy's price.
Do you get it?
So this guy moving his ass price higher for the short period of time is implying that he doesn't
want to take on short exposure he's skewing how wide a spread is based on his internal positioning
his internal risk okay at least for that very very short period of time he's waiting for someone
to come on offset that risk yeah yeah then then say when that happens would it would would
probably just go back to um all the other levels yeah as soon as that as soon as they're outs they've
been offset they can quickly move that that price back down assuming they want to assuming they don't
expect the price to move out of this area.
If this guy starts to aggressively move his prices higher,
these guys are all go into a different state.
The protective mechanism kicks off,
and it's a completely different environment.
None of them want to provide cell liquidity either.
So whilst this is happening,
in this instance, imagine you came and you sold here
removing the risk of the liquidity provider,
so he moves this ask price back down.
Based on that,
I could infer,
that someone just sold to that liquidity provider
because he just moved his ass price down.
I don't know whether you did or not.
I don't know it's Zane doing it.
But because of the liquidity provider
changing his spread at that time
based on the current market condition
where all these guys are the same,
I can infer that there's a seller in the market
at that period of time.
Do you get it?
Immediately, I might hit the bid here somewhere
and then this dealer pushes his
bid price down and the dynamic
you know so the point I'm making is
we're talking about information leakage large traders
they need to split the orders into small pieces
everything they do is trying to hide
the information of the order flow
why do they have to do it on such a technical
such an advanced basis because the amount
of information that leaks
the different variations of information leakage
is so wide but I can analyze
the spreads of liquidity providers
retract information from there
I can analyze how much this
this candelous ticking to retract how much information, you know, to retract what's going on.
You can have specialised data feeds which look at the price updates in millions of times a second
at East liquidity providers to infer which one slower or faster.
There's a broad array of predatory aggressive type entities out there, HFTs,
which analyze all this information at all times to try to get information on edge over everybody else.
So these guys are making it more costly for the large traders.
when they're then transacting a large amount
when they're using execution algos
all of these factors are considered
they're curating their liquidity pools
based on reducing their costs
they're curating or they're coming up with ways
to execute and transact large volume
again to hide information
and reduce their costs
it's a general trend
it has to be done for you to survive
or for you to make a lot of money
or at least to avoid losing a lot of money
so when we're discussing why limit orders move higher it's not a case of like it's just random chance
it has to be done these guys have accepted that if they're going to get filled there is going to
be always some form of information leakage because you're trading with a dealer typically on
disclosed basis by disclosed i mean you're trading with a liquidity provider and they know
who you are they have informational advantages over everybody else it's slightly unfair but that's the
case. So it's never
going to be a perfectly perfect environment
where no information needs.
So if I now want to get filled for $90 million,
you have to accept that you have to
you know, you're not going to get filled at your desired
price. It's likely going to be over a distance
of PIP distance range.
They, I will, I then have options
in instructing these executional goes on an
automated basis to fill my order over this period
of, over this distance, over this period of time
with this level of aggression.
Etc, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
I have all these controls and options given to me.
So whenever you do have, you know, midflow, it's just meta orders, large orders being filled through, you know, child, there's a parent order, and there's subsequent smaller child orders being filled through the methods we've been discussing.
So, you know, liquidity cannot get picked up.
it can follow along with price
I say picked up
by saying picked up I mean
if there was one
one million by limit order here
if I come and I mark
your order sell to hit that
limit order I've grabbed it
it's mine right
so that one million's gone now
I've now filled that order
I've taken the opposite side against it
that order's been picked up
now let's change the equation
imagine i have this one million order
and somebody comes down and hits my order
but they only hit 300k
yeah so i have 700k
yeah you still got to get filled
prior sub-skuddy starts to move away
i then have to my liquidity has to chase behind it
in order for it to get picked up
or there's no the further price moves away
the more uncertain i am about my order getting filled
i want to get it filled it's relatively you know relatively quickly
so i move my liquid
higher here and then any sell order that comes through hopefully picks my order on okay
you get it yeah so if there's sell limit order here and I want to buy I need to go and pick it
up that's all that's all I mean I'm not saying that the liquidity the 700k was grabbed by this guy
and it was moved higher no I moved it higher because the price moved higher yeah yeah okay
that's that's clear that up now so let's just say there's 100 million 10 million grabbed here
90 million left the price starts to be overweight there's 19
million buy limit orders there's relatively thin sell limit orders so market order buying quite easily pushes price through price is moving away this 90 million follows along and we see multiple pickups right let's just say there's i don't know 70 million left over price moves along we have your event highly highly inefficient move out my liquidity remains down here obviously we'd want to so again these are algos they quite
advanced, depending on the level of volatility, depending on how far prices moved, you can
even oversee, you know, so if I instructed the alga, I can watch it doing it. Yeah. You know,
there are options where if you were initially, you know, if I hypothetically wanted and had to get
the 70 million filled, I wanted to do it here, but market environment has changed and might
turn aggressive. The liquidity in this instance, or let's just say there was an event that made me
extra bullish and extra urgent to get long
so I just accepted the price
up here so I'm
aggressively now following price
now due to aggressive following
price comes grabs it grabs it
grabs it grabs it grabs it grabs it grabs it
multiple times here
right price is gone comes back gone
comes back comes back pops up
comes back comes back comes back
in that period alone
I've now gone aggressive
so I'm getting filled quite quickly
at more expensive prices as you can see
I'm following along higher
at higher prices more frequently
it's more expensive
but I'm getting it filled quicker
let's just say there's now
only 30 million left
price then comes down
reaches down
grabs the last of my owner
so as price is dropping
remember I'm still following price as well
the executioner is still following price as well
the buy liquidity has got a thinner here
price grabs I don't know
let's just say this is only 10 million left
now whatever liquidity
remains in this last shelf
that push price to new highs
is it stronger week
it's relatively weaker
it's thinner now
we grab it again
5 million left
price pushes out
some of this 5 million follows
1 million 0.5 million
2 million
this is now only 2 million left
price comes
grabs it
I'm distributed
this liquidity is being distributed
through this automated execution I'll go
as many times
price comes back
wherever price goes
is following along with it
is distributing
within this area until it's hard
any there. But the point
to raise here is the further price travel, the weaker it got
the liquidity. Eventually, the liquidity was so
weak that every time price responded off it, it fell to move anywhere
materially. So during the midflow, there's a whole
bunch of bi-liquity holding price up. It's so
strong that price doesn't even spend a long time there
transacting with it because the buy-liquity is
quickly absorbing any market order sells.
There's already sell weakness, so market order buyers are pushing price through time and time again.
Until this area is drained, price is now coming back, draining whatever by liquidity was here.
After that search out, this run dries off.
It's an independent search.
It's an independent fractal price run.
That surge dries off.
As we draw back into this area, it's very unlike, you know, the liquidity has been drained, basically.
whatever the sellers transact with and match with
they quickly get filled
but the amount of liquidity following along with price
is almost non-existent
the price comes down again
to find the next area of bi-liquity
picks that up
some of it follows along with prices and moves higher
because there's a slight bit of sell weakness there
and again
the buy liquidity is just nonexistent here
any selling pushes price down
some buy liquidity follows along with price
it might market water buyer might push price through
if the buyers are strong
there'd be a whole bunch of buy liquidity
follow along with price as it did here
yeah but it's just not showing it there is it
it's not it's not a case of like showing it
it just isn't there because the buy liquidity
got picked and picked and picked and drained and drained
until this last area was grab grab grab grab
draining most of the inventory available there
so next time when price comes down
there just isn't enough juice
in the liquidity
to hold prices up
in each of these smaller price runs
so any selling that comes through
quickly is able to push price down
to the next area of the next small area
of bi liquidity
so the point here is
the question I asked you is
why and how could you explain
the weakness in bi-responsive
in other words
why is the buy liquidity
not holding price off
and feeding
price into a new high.
It does it successfully here
every time. Yeah, it's because it's already
drained, isn't it? It isn't
enough to juice price and follow a lot
higher and higher and higher. It quickly dries
up. It's like,
you know, let's just say there's 30 million there, yeah?
In the first pickup,
some of the liquidity is filled.
So in this first run down here,
one or two million was sold
into the buy limit orders. So there's
28 million left. Now,
some of that 28 million,
because that move down dries off
any market order buying starts to push price through
some of that 28 million
also follows along with price
let's just say it's only 3 million
3 million follows along
any selling gets filled
selling gets filled until that small
3 million buy liquidity inventory
has failed
then the next sell order that comes through
has to push down
to find the next area of buy liquidity
which is down here
so initially you picked up two
three follow, that's five gone
there's 25 million left
so the next price run
comes and grabs the buy liquidity again
picks up two
three million follows along
but you follow
yeah yeah
and then the same thing happens
we see weak buy responses
rather than price come
feed into this last range
absorb any selling
the market pops back up
because they move down dried off
right move down dry it off
and any buying pushes price out
But as price is pushing out
Some of this liquidity is supporting price
I'm moving along with it, holding you up
So if a seller did turn up here
It finds buy liquidity there's too much of it
For the seller to push price
There's still sell weakness here
Market order buyer pushes price out
The buy liquidity follows price
And it holds it up again
And until price runs out again
So now we just had this whole fractal price swing
composed of thick, thick bi liquidity
holding price up
sellers couldn't push down
until we hit this small area
sellers disappeared and price
there's a huge
there's a bigger cell vacuum here
there's a bigger area of cell weakness
past the high
and price surges out
to the next level of cell liquidity
right
in this high volatile condition
is trading thinly
the lack of the willingness
to buy a higher and higher prices
is almost non-existent
so the liquidity kind of remains down here
once that drives up
and price draws down
the selling, the light selling
pushes price back down
picks up buy liquidity
by that I mean the market order sellers
find the buy liquidity
market order sellers dry off
the move down left behind
relatively thin sell liquidity
any market order buyers push price through
as price pushes through
some of this liquidity
follows along
yeah
now imagine
the buy liquidity wasn't here now
any market order
sell would push price down
and then we come
we grab bi-liquity again
fuck's sake
I fuck that one up
so
the last range
now is weak
the last show
basically the inventory is now weak
so it picks them up
some of it tries to follow along
but as it's following along
the run gets strained
the bi-liquity get strained
so any selling
pushes price down
it goes deeper
to collect the next area
of buy liquidity in that infantry
grabs it
market order sellers dry off there's a bit of weakness in that run market order buyers are able to push price through and the amount of liquidity following price is still not strong enough to feed it higher and higher and higher and higher until we hit this range or we hit that area when a market order buyer buy comes through there's going to be a whole vacuum of sell liquidity here and price will pop out to the next level but there's not enough juice in the buy liquidity that's getting grabbed from here that that is following price from here
At higher and higher prices, it's just not juice.
How can we identify this area as not having enough juice?
How many times it goes into it?
Well, that's after the fact now.
Price came into it after, after.
This area had to be a week already for this to not be able to push to new highs.
Yeah, yeah, that's correct.
So this is reflecting the state of liquidity, the weakness in the buy liquidity.
these price responses are showing you.
I'm saying
if we analysed how the midflow occurred,
we'd be able to see that this area
is very likely to be weak
and we call that the breaker midflow,
the drain of inventory, the sideways, the pop.
You get it.
When the last inventory is strong,
price hardly feeds into it.
It hardly feeds into it.
There's so much by liquidity.
It kind of district,
it basically is present all the time.
other than when we pop out here
what you'll typically see is
price will be relatively low volatility here
and then as we cross the threshold
of the midflow high
there's going to be a huge
it's going to be quite inefficient basically
price well surge through
as price surges through
the amount of transactions at the market
they're just trying up nobody's willing to trade here
nobody's willing to buy it higher and higher prices here
the liquidity remains back down to the inventory
so if I just show you
an example. So here, price is quite stable inside this height on the right. As price pushes through,
bam, right? It doesn't matter which midflow we look at. So I need to start using this tool,
man. All right. So here you have the midflow high. Price is relatively stable inside of it. And then
if you were to, it's hard to see it, we can go back to 1155 or whatever day this is. It would have
surged out. And price dries off. Now, look, it's quite stable.
And then it goes right through his surges.
Every time price pushes through,
so when it's in midflow,
price will pop out,
draw back into the last inventory,
build up because buy liquidity is following along with price.
But as market order pushes through here,
price will typically expand.
It'll become highly, highly inefficient.
The sell liquidity will run away.
The reason being,
there's typically some little amounts of sell liquidity here.
And there's relative, you know,
there's matching going on.
So as buying pushes through,
But as soon as the market order,
at the right time,
pushes and hits here,
basically once a sell liquidity here has been drained,
the next market orders that come through,
the LPs basically,
they go into that protective mode.
They avoid taking on short positions.
So what do they do?
So here they, yeah,
they remove the cell liquidity.
Actually, no, not remove.
what was the word you said
they avoid it
yeah yeah avoid
so the point
really here is look
you Zane has 10 million
sell limit orders here
I'm a liquidity provider providing
a bid and ask
my client
is going long here
I'm like cool I will fill him
short position because I can use
Zane's sell liquidity that's around this area
to match out with you know
matching out yeah yeah right
but eventually Zane's
with Zane's illiquity
has drained
Now my next client goes long
If I go short
I have no way of getting out of it
Number one
Number two
There's a high likelihood price
Will move against me anyway
So I've already taken
Onshore positions
I have to
You know internally
I have to go and look for
A counterparty
For this long order
There might be some sell liquidity
You might book here
Yeah
But as and when price
starts to push out
And I start to move my prices higher
All the other liquidity
Fridays respond
The sell liquidity dries up
they don't the distribution of liquidity is controlled right so if there was sell limit orders here
on some other venue that's not being provided to the market it's all being controlled and price goes
into that highly inefficient price run state inefficient state like we discussed that's the dealer
behavior making the sell liquidity weakness worse but here um literally trying to emphasize
how you will typically have a high price will be relatively stable inside of it then as price
pushes through, bam. Here you have
another high, price is relatively stable
inside of it and then it surges through.
Are these like fractal
extensions, these are fractal
extensions past the highs, aren't they?
Yeah, they're all extensions, yeah.
So look, there's some sell liquidity
in this high, price grabs it, price grabs it.
Once this was drained,
then it pushes through it.
Yeah. Right?
So, going back to what I'm discussing here,
it's a pretty long, wouldn't it, but
it's relevant.
like I said to you price reflects the state of liquidity yeah so in midflow when the midflow
is strong i.e. with as thick, thick buyers and relatively weak sell liquidity price would
surge out dry off the buy liquidity is at the last inventory any light selling could push
price down but because there's so much buy liquidity here think of what a liquidity provider
sees and how their behavior could affect what happens here so
there's huge huge amounts of buy liquidity here
market order sells are pushing price down
like market order selling
but as it comes into the inventory
the dealer does not want to be taking on
short positions
because it's thick thick by liquidity here
yeah right
there's a relatively thin sell liquidity in this move down
thick by liquidity here
from other clients from what the LPs can see
sitting in their own box
the way the spreads are being priced
market wide
actually the spreads will start
to reflect that so there'll be
really competitive bid prices here
where you can buy at
or where you can sell that sorry
you as a client can sell at really
really competitive bid prices
because if you sell to the LP at his
bid they can quickly hedge that off
with a buy liquidity event
it's also very unlikely that
if you were to sell
you'll be selling
you'll be selling enough to make these buyers
to push past these buyers here.
The risk is that somebody buys off the LP
and the LP is now selling with a cell weakness.
Right?
So here, as you can think about the amount of times
the LP has to change their risk-taking position.
Up here, do you think they want to buy yourself?
Their willingness to provide buy liquidity
is going to be all this non-existent here.
Because as price stretches out,
the buy liquidity is left thin
so when the LP receives any
market order sells
they themselves are not going to be willing
to take on long positions up there
they buy they withdraw their bid
and the cell volume has to chase it
as price runs down here
they come into a thick pool of buy liquidity
so any market order of the cells
that come through here the liquidity provider
can fill it and take on the
opposite side of it and hedge
out of that trade because they know there's a
huge like there's a huge base or shelf of support here in you know a few minutes later basically
now even though there's a huge amount of support here if any market order buy comes through
there's a thin distribution of some liquidity left behind and they move down the LP then wants
to avoid taking on short positions so if a market order long comes through to avoid adverse
selection to avoid taking on short positions the ask price has to draw away from the market
order, pulled the volume higher
in order to find sell liquidity
there. So, like, here we
saw the buy liquidity draw away from price,
here we saw the sell liquidity draw away from price
based on
the amount of buy liquid is strength of the market.
You can just imagine it's happening
time and time again
and the smallest of scales.
You know, the more you explain how
these LPs work is
the more, like, I just think
these algorithms
are just crazy.
On one hand, the job is to provide liquidity,
but on the other, they can't provide liquidity all the time.
They cannot be taking on short positions here.
It's ridiculous, bro.
They will lose money if they do that.
Under this condition, where there's weak sell liquidity already in the market,
they'll have ask prices available,
but if you were to capture the ass price,
it's likely they'll last lock you.
So you try to buy it here.
You got filled for your trade, yeah?
Right after your trade is filled,
they reserve the right to reject it.
they reserve the right to reverse that trade number one
number two if they were going to fill you
they would themselves have to aggressively buy ahead of you
and then provide a sell liquidity to you
so you try to buy here
they would before they
before they fill a short against you is
they would have to go and buy themselves
build the inventory so they can sell back to you right
that's one of the options they have
under these fast conditions basically it's just unreasonable
to expect them to behave the way they do
to behave
outside of the way they do.
I want to eventually move on
from talking about specific
things that everything I'm talking about
is hypothetical, yeah?
There's more generic ways
of discussing it. So here
there's 2 million, 2 million, 2 million, 2 million, 2 million, 2 million.
There's a 50 million market order long
that one liquidity provider receives.
He receives it here.
the first price available for sell limit orders,
sell liquidity is here.
He has a few options.
He can decide to keep this $50 million in-house
and pull your volume higher.
So his ask price moves up here
and your volume chases higher
to get matched with this $2 million.
Or he can decide that you're trying to buy $2 million here.
This liquidity provider showing $2 million
at a slightly higher price.
You can buy there and sell back to you
at this price.
So he can
externalize the order flow.
This is keeping it internal
or he can externalize the
order flow. Under a condition
like this, you know, when
I say that dealers today, they like to
internalize and they used to externalize
it's never that black and white.
There's going to be times where a liquidity
provider is forced to externalize
his order flow. There's absolutely
no way that he can find liquidity
in-house. Yeah.
And if he wants to fill this market order
50 million long, he has to go
and buy it in the market
from another liquidity provider from another venue
and then sell it back to you.
And if you as a client
are consistently forcing the liquidity provider
to externalize the order flow,
you're making him behave in a way
which is costly for him, number one.
It's likely that he's going to start
to give you wider spreads.
There's not going to like you as much.
There's various different things that can happen.
So eventually I'll be like,
you know, here is, you know, all the LPs would have been externalising.
Nobody wants to take on short positions here.
If somebody wanted to go longer against them and they had, you know, if somebody wanted
to buy it, they asked price, some of them might have had sell liquidity there that they didn't
even provide out to the market.
Yeah.
They just kept the inventory for themselves and started to provide in small amounts around here.
Once the huge shot of volume dried off.
So there's a number of actions and behaviours.
that can take place, all of them combined at the same time can occur.
So, generically speaking, when I'm talking about these specific outcomes during midflow,
it kind of makes me cringe at times.
I'm like, yeah, you know, it's a level of discussion that I'm not entirely comfortable
with saying that an LP does this exactly at this minute, you know, it's just unreasonable.
There's a number of things they could be doing at all times.
Yeah, you're just given specific examples of what can't have.
happen and the effects of that the effects are you know if they externalize the order so there's
a price run up left behind relatively thin by liquidity in that move up hits a pocket of sell limit
orders I should say there's 10 million here the market order buying is absorbed by the 10
million sell limit orders there's 9 million left the move up left really thin by
liquidity one million spread across these four dots so 250 each 250k each a light light market order
seller 500k half a million five lots will be able to push price right down to these to these two
dots right now in essence you're not going to be selling based on the liquidity present in the market
here you're selling at the bid price of the liquidity provider do you get it yeah
The liquidity provider receives your 500k order.
Based on the available weakness and the state of liquidity of this price run,
they themselves avoid taking on short positions on an automated basis.
They pull their bid price lower in order to find the liquidity to match it for you.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Price, you end up getting slipped.
Market impact is you get slipped.
That is exactly the same as if they, you know, you tried to sell 500K here.
if they themselves went and sold 500k here to sell it back to buy it back off you
the effect is the same prices still drove down so whether they internalize it or externalize it
the effect remains the same that's why i'm talking in specifics do you get it yeah
they can't keep it internal the price will move down anyway they can externalize it and still
that'll cause information leakage and everybody else will start to sell ahead of you and it might even
become more expensive for you then for your fireman
hundred k to get filled because think about it this way there is this 500k here across those two dots
if the LP takes it they're not going to give it to you at the most competitive price but it's very likely
that when the LP took you off the other LP they themselves turned into sellers and they then took
the next two price levels for you and then you were forced to accept like the fifth price level
yeah so you get slipped you get slipped quite hard and it wouldn't ever be that much it wouldn't
really be seven pips for something as small as 500k only 0.2 pips 0.1 pip but just imagine if there
was a 550 million order here it's quite easily you get slip seven pips there you get filled for you
seven million over some weighted average price here but by rated average i mean if you got filled for
49 million here and one million here yeah the average weight of volume was around this price
that's volume weighted average price
so yeah
anyway let's explain it this way
so up here the buy liquidity weakness
thicker sell liquidity
the LP wants to avoid
taking on long position
so any market order selling
they pull the volume down
by this point that market order volume
has been stretched and filled
has found some areas of liquidity here
the market order selling is dried off
left behind weakness in the sell liquidity
any market order buy that comes through the LP
of voice taken on short positions
and has to go and find the sell liquidity in the book
essentially forcing the volume higher chasing after it.
In each of these instances,
why is this high stopping here
and not pushing to new highs?
Why is it stopping inside of the last range?
Because we're in a state of broader midflow
and we're seeing sell liquidity
except lower and lower prices.
There had to be strung sell liquidity here anyway
to absorb the market order buying
and not only that
feed the move down
to new lows and continue
driving it lower.
So, you know, there was 40 million
sell limit orders there. A portion
of it at least would typically
follow as well. So as price
dried off here, the market orders dried off,
some sell liquidity turned up there. And simultaneously
because this low is weak,
it's hitting, let's say a weaker area by
liquidity, that it has to be the case if we're in bearish midflow. If we're in
bearish midflow, the bi liquidity is always going to be weak. So we're now grabbing that
relatively weak area of bi liquidity. There was 10 million here. We've grabbed some of it. There's only
seven million left. Followed, you know, price starts to move up. So some of that seven million
follows price. Let's say two of it. Two million follow price. It got picked up, picked up, picked up,
until there was nothing there. Market order sell push price down. It's five million left here. You know,
when price picks this up, it grabs some, it grabs some, it grabs some, it grabs some.
But imagine there's only $5 million bi-liquity feeding price here.
And in this instance, we're seeing price grabs that liquidity, grabs-sell equity,
and there's $40 million holding price down.
It's quite, you know, in this instance, LPs will be relatively cautious to take in our long positions.
Any market order is selling, or any market orders, basically,
the likelihood of them pushing through the $5 million before the $40 million is quite evident.
And even if market order buyers push through the 40 million here,
it's likely there'd be a huge amount of sell liquidity in the actual big shelf.
So price pushes out.
Market order sells dry off.
Sell liquidity chases price down again and again and again.
What happens then when this area is now eventually drained?
So this large amount of sell liquidity has been grabbed and grabbed and grabbed
until there's a relatively small portion of the sell equity left down here.
Price will feed off it.
some of it will follow
a price,
some of it will feed
this move down.
But the duration of the feeding,
the intensity of the feeding
is not likely to be that strong.
You'll quickly dry off
and price will have,
any buying will have to push deeper
into the inventory
to find sell liquidity.
The market orders dry off again,
picks up some of the sell liquidity.
Some of it follows price down
as there's weak bids,
market order selling's pushing price down,
the sell equity follows.
But again,
there's not enough sell equity
to continue following and holding price down.
So any bid that comes through, bam.
So the difference that we've seen here is,
here where we fed off the last inventory,
it fed it to new lows quite successfully,
quite distinctively and quite well.
Here we're feeding off the last inventory,
but it's failing, price goes deeper into the inventory.
It's failing, it goes deeper into the inventory.
Yeah, it shows weakness.
It shows weakness in the available cell liquidity.
exactly that's what I want you to see.
So the cell limit order weakness here
had to exist before these
price responses showed you.
We're deciphering whether this is weak
or strong through the mid-flow characteristics
before the fucking lower high is put in anyway.
So we class this as weak, let's just say,
it's not actually weak, but let's just class this as weak,
then price grabs the buy liquidity,
then it, and let's say we went long here,
then it returns back to the inventory
and we see multiple attempts back to our entry point
where it's making us quite nervous, basically.
But the point here is the characteristics in these price run
in how they're forming,
i.e. the failing to push to new lows,
actually the buyers are pushing deep into cell inventory.
That is for that moment in time reflecting favourable probabilities.
It's reflecting that there's cell weakness there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's true.
That's why I say, finally coming back to the original point,
that's why I say this type of high apex variation
is not unfavorable
you know it's less favorable than this one
I would always opt
I would all if I had to choose if I could choose
I would always want to trade here
yeah you can be in and out quick
but this is still somewhat favorable
because the buy inventory just hasn't got enough juice
to feed price higher and higher
it's getting drained and yeah it's getting drained
and sell limit order is actually holding
holding price down now
So, you know, it's a long-wondered way of explaining things.
It's quite important, though.
There's different variations of the ways, you know, price can show weakness.
This is more pronounced weakness.
This is obviously not as weak.
But the characteristics and the response are showing us that the buy inventory is weak.
Now, at any given second, this could start to push to new highs.
But then the probabilities will change.
And we have to track price as it updated.
all the time to assess
that our probabilities are changing
again because me and you can't tell the future
we just can't
and we know that probabilities can change
instantaneously
we can't assume
that that probability of right now
let's say it's 99 to 1
will be the same
five minutes later
yeah actually
I think on Friday
I went on Twitter
I saw RM was in a short
under pound and he
said that he was going to go lower
but he said
he was tracking it
and yeah
probabilities change
and it went all the way back up
so yeah
oh did you ask him
no no no
so basically
he put his chart
saying it was going to go lower
and then
I just check GU anyway
just see what it's doing
and yeah it went all the way back up
all right so that price movement
it could only have gone back up
so when he expects price to go lower
no let's just say price
was here he expects price to sell off yeah yeah it's because he deemed that there's
weak buy liquidity year there's not enough buy juice to hold price up and continue feeding
price and you know etc etc but what if he was right and then something happened
within this small two three five 10 one hour two hour period two day period
where there's now brand new by willingness by liquee that turns up here yeah he probably
change just like that.
Now, the probabilities have changed
but we don't know it because I can't tell that
there's bi-limber orders there. I haven't got the capacity or
the information or the data or the money to access
the data. But the price
will show it. Yeah.
The price will reflect it.
And the price updates
always reflect the state of liquidity. Price
always reflects the state of liquidity. Price is
a function of liquidity.
So we can use that simply
to always be aware and update
in-tune, connected.
up to date with what the underlying condition or strength or weakness of the market is
and based of the updates and prices we can extract a lot of information especially if I have a
short bias prices now showing me that immediately the sell weakness here if I have a short
position here the likelihood of price coming back to my short position and against it is
almost you know is very very high before I've taken a loss I can update my positioning
I can cancel the trade I can move my stop down or what I
you want to do, yeah, you can manage that risk, I can manage that change of probability.
This individual outcome means nothing, by the way.
He could have been right, and he could have had a short position there, for example,
and the buy liquidity never turned up there, and the probabilities remained favourable
and price did tank.
You never know which one is going to happen.
We never know the future, but what we do know is that the future will have to, basically,
you know, time doesn't just fast forward.
it's in you know time and information is embedded into price over time so as price updates is showing us
what's going on based off the new updates and price information we can determine if probably
these have changed or not so slightly nuanced he should have been able to determine somewhere
around here which is like a shift in the state of liquidity that if he's short around these
levels he needs to just get out he needs to abandon his idea for now right so
this Bayesian inference
tracking new information
and placing greater weight
on new information than historical old information
what kind of time frames do you look at
if you want to
keep if you want to track price
would you go down onto
it depends
it depends so like
imagine I thought
the Sallikuri
here
yeah
it makes sense for me to look at in a relatively
small time frame
because if I scale out
I won't be able to see it
imagine if I thought
there's sell liquidity here
I can't really see
why there would be
sell liquidity on this time frame
maybe the only way
I could identify
that there's a huge area
of sell liquidity
is if I was to scale
out to the time frame
and find that
that's actually a five minute base
for example
do you get it
yeah
that's actually the last
sideways inventory
that push price out
that's the big shelf
in this instance
So the point I'm really making here is there's no
There's no special art to it
To what time frame I use
It's based on the level of view
Or the level of zooming in that I need
If I need a suit, you know, in here
I can't see shit on the five minute chart
Yeah, you have to go deeper in
I need to look inside of it as if it's a microscope
I use the time
Just to get a close of view
Or a further out view
Typically
I'll spend a lot of time on the one minute charts
Because I'm tracking price so closely
I want to know how it responds
off the liquidity there
and the liquidity there
and when this high
was pushing through
I want to see
how it's responding
off the sell liquidity there
and I can't see that shit
on the five minutes
so I'll be typically
spending a lot of time
in the one minute
but never basing my decisions
just off the one minute
I'm not trading the one minute chart
I'm not trading the one minute
price runs
I'm just using it as a tool
to get a closer view
of things when I need it
to make more informed
decisions about what I'm trying to do
If I'm trying to time the exhaustion point of this short hair,
there's fucking no way I'm doing it in a five minute.
I can't see anything.
As soon as I scale down,
now we see, okay, the weakness of the price broke the last inventory,
it pops up.
Here is a really, you can just look at the candles.
The candles, they're closing at the highs.
They're closing at the highs.
They're not pulling back, basically.
It's becoming more and more inefficient as it goes on.
The ticking here will be completely different.
compared to the other highs here.
So if I was trying to time the short,
if I was trying to time the shore
of this highly inefficient price run,
there was no way I'd be able to time it
on the five minute shop.
Yeah.
I had to look inside of it
to get a more granular view,
a more detailed view of what's going on.
So you know,
that's when I use the timeframes.
So.
Yeah, so you only go down as much as you need, basically, then.
I only go down as much as I need.
I go down to get a closer view of things
which are not visible or evident
on the higher time
which is all the time.
It's all the fucking time.
If I was trying to assess
where this price run will stop,
I would kind of be on a tick chart
to one minute to five minute.
I'm scrolling through timeframes
relentlessly.
Right?
So here, price looks really quite inefficient.
It's coming in to buy liquidity here.
There's scope for it to draw back up
and fill this extension back to there.
Right?
fills the extension back up to
it. Price would have been
quite jumpy into this last dealing range
there, but as it draws
down, I could make a relative
assumption that I don't expect the buy
liquidity in this low to be that strong
because of the broader context available
that I could only get off, you know, so
the buy, we basically just
broke shelf. We just broke the last inventory.
We did our
sideways pop. So here's
your midflow. Here's your break
of inventory, sideways and pop.
And then we've now just broke that inventory there.
This is that.
All right?
So the scope are now prices returning back down to this.
I wouldn't want to be a buyer here.
I'd actually take the position where any response,
I would expect it to be a weak response
because the buy liquidity is showing weakness.
Did you get it?
This low, pushing past the shelf,
is already confirming the weakness.
Why the fuck would I take a retest of a weak area
of already a weak area,
which is feeding.
Did you get it?
Yeah,
it's just all week or not.
That doesn't mean price can't do that.
It can,
but it's a lower probability.
Over time,
you will not make money
taking retests or fucking
shitty laws like that,
bro.
You will not make money.
Consistently at least.
Right?
So here,
it responds.
I didn't expect that response
to be strong
and price traded through it.
Yeah.
So on a granular level,
every single point where price is going
I'm tracking it in that sense
but within the frame or context
of the higher time frame.
Yeah, that's cool.
It makes sense now.
Right?
So every single bit of price I'm tracking
I'm trying my best basically.
You're not going to get it perfect.
I'm trying my best to be as closely connected to it
and aware of it and what is doing,
the levels is hitting,
the location of the price swing,
the location I mean,
I knew that this circle was that.
Did you get it?
I knew that this is the show.
that needs the whole price just broke the shelf
I wouldn't know this by weakness all of this price run
this is typically before the reversal
and it ends up
it ends up being there
right
I actually shorted
I think here
which is not my usual
way of trading
the reason I didn't short this
it was way too fast to me
I got I was bare surprised with this broker
I was like what did you see that second time
let me just show you
this low was weak
I expected this to go through it
right
so we basically saw price run out
try to get short there
missed my level cool I couldn't get short
price gave broke the last inventory the shelf
yeah broke the last shelf
leaving weakness in the residual area
typically when we pushed through the shelf as well
it's kind of already confirmed
the weakness had to exist before the price broke shelf
but then as we push through shelf as well
there's like a self-reinforcing effect
where by liquidity
we'll typically draw away
back down to around the core
but from early in the morning
I assessed the call as weak
because it didn't really hit
nothing anything significant
so as we broke down here
I was at cool we'll get a shelf retest
which that's why it is
shelf retest is that
and then we should push into midflow
we did push into midflow
so as it was a midflow
was quite confident that it would break down
it came down
to the shelf of this move down
and the shelf
the price got up over the shelf and retested it
it came down to the shelf retest of this
core
put the lower
cool I expected that load to go
it had a deep test of shelf
we already broke midflow here
so now we had a deep test of shelf
it was mainly a question of
is this going to have enough juice
anywhere inside of here
to continue pushing down
and the answer was basically
is very unlikely.
The price came up,
the low held,
which is indicated
the cell inventory
is failing to push past the buyers
time and time again,
draining the cell inventory.
It became evident here,
it was a low volume stay,
it became evident here
that we're not going to break past
the low inside of this shelf.
Yeah.
While it's holding inside of the shelf,
you get it.
What I didn't expect is
for this motherfucker to do that.
I know.
It's always a chance of it doing that.
just didn't expect it.
What I would have thought is it would have drew back up into here
and responded and worked its way through, if that.
So because I didn't expect it to break out,
I wasn't ready with that level.
I expected it to drift through and did you get it?
So if I had, you know, if I did my job, basically,
I would have had that level prepared on the left
and I would have been shortened it there.
Yeah, that just reinforces what you said,
how probabilities can change instantly.
yeah like that new event happened there was a headline here that said
the macron is going to concede on the fishing some mag bollocks like that
basically there's a there's an issue with the fishing rights I guess
on the France and the UK channel yeah what do you call it
there's a channel in between the UK and France yeah and there's right now I think
like a European Fisheries Commission so any
fishing that the UK does has to meet the regulations that the European Fisheries Commission set out.
Because we're now moving out of, you know, because we're leaving the European Union,
the UK wants to retain most of the control over that channel and how much fish they take out of it
or whatever madness they do.
That's been a contentious issue because Europe's consistently refused that they're going to let
the UK, you know, do what the fuck they want.
They want them to continue abiding by the fish.
commission's rule or whatever.
So this was all, this was a problem.
This was, this was one of the things stopping your, the Brexit deal being reached or the
Brexit, whatever.
So on Friday, the prime minister of France came out and said, or he was preparing to say
something which might let the UK do what the fuck they want to do, something along those
lines.
Can you see how, if me and you were negotiating and I'm trying to buy a car of you and you're
saying, no, I won't budge on the price, I won't budge on the price, I won't
on the price we want budge on the price and then you suddenly turn around and said how much do you
want to take the price down you get it you're showing me signs that you're now open yeah
seems good for you then yeah and it was a similar kind of dynamic there I don't read into the news
that much I'm just kind of aware of what they're talking you know what they're talking about
yeah so that's why I can't tell you super specific things about the rules whatever but yeah
as soon as that headline dropped the probability
you know, the state of liquidity changed.
So the sell limit order has disappeared,
the market order buy started to come through.
And that then immediately changes the probability
of what's going to happen next,
which is price is going to spike
rather than continue selling off.
You get it?
So the probability is changed
that the state of liquidity changes,
the state of liquidity response to new information.
The new information comes from various sources.
You can have economic data,
you can have order flow-based information,
which is the primary.
resource of information if you ask me it's the most important information economic data on the
likes it's definitely important because or economic or geopolitical information is important
because right now there could be a fucking a missile coming to the UK and if the market's open
and it becomes aware of a missile coming to the UK the buy liquidity disappears both there's
nobody buying the pound yeah it's likely it goes to flash crash territory then so yeah like
at any given point
any number of variables
can combine
and affect the market
the effect on the market
will be the state of liquidity changes
and here you're seeing the extreme
changing state equity
you can just see it
there's no way for that price run
to move up that fast
if there was a lot of sell liquidity there
right it's impossible
yeah it wouldn't happen
the volatility is a function of
a lack of sell liquidity
here price just
sliced through it
it's like again there's a pokey of ear
there was a pokey of ear was created
so yeah in that sense
probability it can change instantaneously
we like I'm aware that this can
happen yeah
how chaos has been doing it
almost for the last month now
ever since the start of October
it's been doing these months spikes
based off headlines
it's expected
it's not too much of a surprise to me
the point I'm really making here is
my expectations
have developed in tune with what's possible
based on experience.
The same will happen for you
on a much more frequent scale
because you're newer.
You don't know what you don't know,
so there's more for you to learn
so you're going to learn much faster than I am right now.
You get it.
So when you're tracking price
and you're looking at apex high variations,
we'll see some like this,
you'll see some like this,
you'll see the really, really unfavorable
ones that I always cut them
you'll see some like this
there'll be subtle differences in the way each of these form
there'll also be things like this
where the high gets put in and then it comes all the way
back on you and before it goes down again
you're going to experience all of these
that would be a shit one to be in that wood
yeah by this point you're like fuck it you either
take my stop or you don't
you leave that one to God but
The point I make it, your reference point of understanding, your reference point of what's possible in each individual stage of the price swing, whether it's the high, whether it's midflow, whether it's the shifting point, shelf retest, anything, you will have experienced it so many times, so frequently, and all the different variations of them, that eventually you will have a really, really wide, I guess, ocean of experiences and possible.
a knowledge of what's possible
so if anything happens
you will have likely
have considered what the most likely
thing is what price should
do should do
just to make sure you're aware of all
you're not like court of God
by price doing something you've experienced
it before it's likely
when you experienced it before you got fucked over
so in the future you look for it
you make sure you don't get fucked over
by it again so you integrate an approach
into your process of again
and Bayesian analysis
or by Asian influence
where you're tracking
in common information
you're always
reviewing probabilities
you never take things
for granted
you consider multiple outcomes
you know in this high
any of these highs
can fail
you will experience them
failing so
and you don't know
whether they're going to fail or not
so you have to see
you have to anticipate
how they could fail
to make sure you don't get
caught off God
etc etc
so in every single instance
you'll be considering
multiple outcomes
which we'll be discussing soon.
But as of right now,
hopefully what we discussed about
midflow made sense.
Let me have a lot.
It's really just the...
Bro, do you mind giving me
five minutes?
I just don't have a cigarette.
Yeah, yeah, that's fine.
And then what I'll do,
I'll come back and I'll introduce you to the price swing,
full price swing template, I guess,
is that lorries.
But there's things on that price swing
that he's never discussed.
and he never talks about mid-flow,
he never talks about,
he just has pointless shit on there, yeah?
We're just looking at the structure.
Yeah.
I don't give a fuck about the names
he wants to give it,
but we're just looking,
that's a very, very good price swing.
Very nice price swing.
We're going to break this down.
And then I'm going to set you a task
to go and start identifying these swings.
There's also like a 12-part series video
that you can watch.
I think I've already seen, yeah,
I've already seen the swing,
like the point of release and stuff like that.
Yeah, yeah, a little, yeah.
Yeah, so...
I'm just going to introduce you to ret then set you a test to start going, identifying them on a chart.
We'll actually go through examples of some that I've done in the past just to again, you know, finally complete what this swing is, all the different parts of it.
The problem will be, you might be able to see it on historical charts, but this is a price swing also.
You can find the shelf on this one.
Find the shelf on that one.
It's a bit more difficult, right, even though both are price swings.
and then
you know like I said
there's more clear
there's highly
highly clear examples
and there's like less
there's more ambiguous examples
you have to train your eyes
to see them
that's why we start off
in historical charts
then it's a case of
using the price swing
template
and the stages
in the price swing
to actually help
contextualize live prices
if I asked you
what could this do
or what stage is this in
right now
you should be able to answer that
then you should be like because of this stage
and the price swing for you know
you should be able to assess what's more likely to happen
than not you follow them
you should be able to use the price swing
to set realistic expectations
of what price should do
based on the other price swings
we know price swings are consistent because they happen
time and time and time again
they're infinitely going to happen
but that doesn't mean just because
you're now seeing this particular price swing
that it's going to be successful.
All right?
So, you know, I'm sure you can tell me
what should this price swing do?
I'll guide you, yeah?
What levels are these?
Yeah, residual levels.
What is this hitting?
What's that low hitting?
Residual levels?
Yeah, residual, yeah.
You should probably, like, do that,
come back into here, then...
Okay, you're good on the specifics.
That's fine.
But it should really go into bearish-med flow
and you're just talking about the characteristics, yeah?
It should go into bearish-med flow
and draw it right back down to the core
if it's going to respond.
Yeah, yeah.
But I can build a case for why it should do that.
Has it gone past like a bigger shelf here or something?
Higher time frame price, yeah.
And that would be classed as technically breakout accumulation.
Now, here we've had conflicting scales.
In lifetime, you're going to have conflicting skills.
We have to come up with a solution for that.
we also have to come up with a solution for the chance that it does run down
and it will continue for this load to fail
we have to be able to navigate or identify which one of those scenarios is happening
it could go up it can go down how do I know which one's happening
well I need to start using fractal maybe this price swing forms of fractal apex
bullish midflow etc etc but in other case I have the ability
I'm not saying you won't I right now have the ability to know the possibilities I know
I know what price could do, should
do, could do, I know what to look
for, what each story could look like.
My, you know, my
accuracy and my prediction is likely
going to be more informed and, you know, my prediction
is likely going to be a more informed
one than, let's say, someone that
hasn't experienced price swings. Yeah, definitely.
So you have to build that ability and skill.
Nobody can give it to you. You're going to make
mistakes. You're going to be wrong so many
times. You know,
things trick you as well. Like you'll see
the scenario in a higher time frame environment
with this lower time frame scenario
consistently breaks the upside.
So your basic set
standard will be, every time you see this,
it should go up.
Then what environment is going to occur, then it's just going to
fail every single time, 20 times in a row.
That's going to test who you are.
That's going to test your ego
basically. Because who the
fuck, you've seen
this work many, many times are run over.
you fucking think
the general kind of
dynamic then is
people want to quit their work
and start being a full-time trader
because they've had their right environment
you know
they've experienced
they have
like experienced
favorable price action
right
they've seen it work in a certain environment
for a period of time
that makes them somewhat confident
which rightly so you should be confident
but when the environment changes
and that particular price behaviour
doesn't work in the same way
or you trade your relation shorter
you have to change the way you trade
they start losing 10, 15, 20 times in a row
you get it wrong 10, 15, 20 times in a row
that challenges that exact observation
you made about the previous environment
you get it
you made an observation that this particular pattern
works and then it stops working
Yeah, level up
You might just even think that you were just lucky
That's probably more appropriate
what will typically happen what I've seen is if I
I'll be honest with you people they'll take those exercises
in that environment they'll start trading live with a small account
and then the environment changes they go bust
they lose everything and then they come back to me like oh why did this work
then why did that work then I'm like you're a fucking dickhead bro
you are not like I am not a good trader
if I'm winning 10, 10 15 trades in a row that doesn't make you a good trader
a good trader recognizes which environment is what
so if I recognize that this is the environment
to trade this way and then I press it
then yes sick I'm a good trader
and then as soon as the environment changes
and I am I able to adapt to that
then I'm a good trader
yeah you get it
if the environment changes and I'm still trading in a way
which is not conducive anymore for that state of liquidity
then that's just the fault of the person isn't it
it's a fault of the person and then that's what you call lucky
You only won because you were lucky, bro.
You only won in those 20 trades in a row
is because you were lucky.
And, you know, so you can kind of trick yourself.
But outside of that, I don't expect you to be trading live.
Outside of that, what you might do is it can challenge
like your confidence in taking a particular trade
or it can challenge your confidence in your ability to select levels
and make you question things.
It's necessary or it's inherent.
By that what I mean is,
It's natural for you to experience those, like, the adversity, that feed those feelings of, am I doing it right?
You're operating in the unknown.
You don't know the full picture.
You never know the full picture in trading because you don't know the future.
And you're trying to predict the future, basically.
If I had to oversimplify it, trading price runs, you're trying to predict future price moves, yeah?
You need edge and all the stuff you've discussed.
So, yeah, that is going to be about 70% of where your learning happens.
in building your ability to track price,
experience the dynamics of live prices,
using the visual price framework,
which is a tool to navigate prices,
alongside having to navigate change levels of volatility,
change in environments,
never know in the future,
all these are things that you have to navigate in.
Or, you know, yeah, how do I call it?
You know, what solution do you have for not known the future?
What solution do you have for price becoming extremely volatile
within the next minute?
what solution do you have for if price starts to expand in a higher time frame
and efficiency it basically turns into a higher time frame price run where it stops responding
off your levels and it starts doing this for the next 15 hours yeah you have to think of
this all before you you take your trade basically hopefully yeah yeah not every single trade
you take but there should be a period in the day where you make yourself aware but that's fine but
how do you know that this price run here is going to be the one that continues for the next 15 hours
early, early on? Most people will tell you, oh yeah, it was one of those price runs after the top 10
losses in a row. What tool or what solution do you have for identifying changes in the state
of volatility, changes in the state of, changes in like the price run, changes in the environment
as quickly as possible.
These are real solutions
that you need to experience
that I'm going to basically
make you experience
and it's going to lead to a whole
bunch of adversities,
it's going to lead to a whole bunch
of you questioning yourself.
So I'm just kind of making you aware
this is exactly what it is.
There's definitely solutions for it.
The solutions are tied,
the specific steps of the solutions,
but they're tied directly
to your ability.
They're tied directly
to how well you've experienced
then how well you've engaged with price.
So basically,
the solution to this would be the characteristics within this price run
basically showing you it's not going to,
it's not likely to respond.
If you did take a long trade here,
the response and how price,
you know,
how price responded off your level,
it would show weakness anyway.
You know how I said?
Price reflects state of liquidity.
You want to go long here.
So you buy it.
the way price responds the impact after you know the level where you expect
sell exhaustion and buy strength yeah the ticking and everything of it yeah the response
won't show you the strength this is what's showing you that is cell weakness and buy strength
yeah yeah here in this environment you're going to see something almost exactly the
opposite a smaller version of this price will try to move try to move try to you know the low
will try to hold, try to hold, try to hold,
and the characteristics of the response
will show weakness in the bi-liquidy.
Yeah.
Right?
The cell bases will hold or something combined.
Yeah?
So you will,
the solution to not,
the solution to identifying changes in the state of volatility
is, first of all,
experiencing the characteristics of those long-winded price runs
which don't stop for many, many hours.
What does characteristics look like?
And also,
if you're trading at the thinnest point in liquidity you should normally get like a two
three four five pip response that's somewhat manageable you can manage that response
and if none of those things work then basically the solutions they're not appropriate
if you get it but yeah if those solutions don't work basically you can tell me to phone call
yeah they do work um there is
mean you won't take losses. I'm not going to say
you will take losses. There's human error.
There can be times with, you had to buy
a limit order and price just gap straight through it.
There's nothing you can do about that. These are all
random outcomes.
But over time,
you will shift your perspective on
on like
having to be right about
the direction. You can be totally wrong about the
direction and price selling off.
Buy it here and get out because the trade
wasn't developing like you needed to.
Right? You can take a long
position here anticipating price filling this inefficiency back to the back to the core but
the characteristics in how it does that and how price responds how you you know it should
reflect your trade idea how will you identify the characteristics of buy strength only
your very experience and tracking price would you see what price looks like when the
bids are strong and the sellers a week i.e. you get apex characteristics
because price reflects state of liquidity.
The sell liquidity in this shelf
was not strong to hold buyers down.
Actually, the sell liquidity was weak
and the buyers pushed through.
Shelf retest and price pushed into like a small midflow.
This all reflects the existing cell weakness
and the bias strength.
If I took a trade here,
without knowing the future,
if I took a trade at that low,
the characteristics I'm looking for
should be ones that reflect the cell weakness and bias strength.
yeah definitely
there shouldn't be
characteristics that reflect
by weakness
if I'm going along
before we can put ourselves
in that position though
we need an initial response
so before I can go
before you know
I'm in a position
to manage the trade
and see if it's giving
characteristics of strong
you know buy liquidity
and weak sell liquidity
I need to be in a manageable response
where I've taken my entry
and price has given me
this a bit of this
cushion, this caution of profit.
And now with that cushion of profit, I can determine, based on how price is moving, if the
sellers are strong or the buyers are strong. If I'm long, which one do I? What do I need?
You need the seller to be weak, the buyers to be strong?
Yeah. One of them or combination of them. I need weakness in the shelf liquidity and
strength in the bids and the subsequent price action will reflect that.
Yeah.
But imagine you brought it here without knowing whether the buyers, the sellers are strong.
You're not in a manageable position now.
Price could go, you know, for it to invalidate your trade, it will have to go against you and you will have to take a fuller loss.
Whereas if you got in your trade here, you have this cushion of profit.
You've got more space and time to decide if this is developed like a winner or loser.
So how do we put ourselves in that position?
is by trading at the point of exhaustion
if you trade with
is the thinnest sell liquidity
and thicker by liquidity
if you trade on that condition
for this very very very specific condition
is 100% guaranteed price will go your way
initially
so down here is 99 to 1
highly highly likely
price will go your way
but as soon as price comes back up to the small shelf
2, 3, 5, 7 pips away
the probability is a much more balanced now.
It could even be down to 50-50.
Do you get it?
I do not want to buy or sell when it's 50-50,
or 60-40, or 70-30, or 80-20.
I ideally want to be trading under the point of exhaustion
that puts me in the manageable position
and then I can review incoming price action and information
to determine if I want to hold on or not.
Yeah, what's more probable to happen.
Now, we can definitely identify, like,
like broader like so this is a price swing yeah depending on where it is in the higher time frame
because this is only one minute depending on where it is in the higher time frame i might deem that
everything inside of this high or beneath it is weak so before i even took this long position
i had an idea of a bigger trade yeah but those bigger trade expectations they don't always play
out in exactly the way you want them to so it's much harder for you to like get those big trades
all the time.
Over time, you'll build your ability to identify them
through experience, through using timeframes,
through using higher time frame price
from context, et cetera, et cetera.
You will be able to identify them,
but I'll be quite frank with you.
The big trades, that's not a big trade, by the way,
but it is relatively big.
It's like 70 pips.
Oh, shit.
The big trades come around four or five times a month.
I'll be honest with you.
I do not catch 60, 70 pips moves more than that.
a month most of my money is made by catching 30 pips yeah 25 pips 30 pips 36 pips 33 pips on gbp usd if you
were trading something like gold then yeah you'll catch 100 pips for joke but you'll also have other
execution issues as well because it's an illiquid piece of shit it's fucking terrible um so yeah
obviously depends on the characteristics of the underlying currency pair but um yeah most of my money is
made by catching six, seven,
our trades on relatively small
hip distance moves. I'm not trying to be
spectacular. I don't give a fuck about catching the big
moves. I want to make money, bro.
And I'm trading the volatility conditions
that are a function of the microstructure, the order
flow dynamics, the liquidity dynamics, etc.,
that happens on a repeated basis. It's quite
unique in FX because you get liquidity on both
sides of the market. You always get
liquidity on both sides of the market
until you don't, yeah? Until you
you have those very highly event-driven states.
About 90% of the time,
sorry,
about 70% of the time,
we're going to be seeing more balanced prices.
So balance, balance, balance, balance, balance,
and then moves for which short periods of time.
You can definitely anticipate those moves.
You can definitely weight those moves out.
You'll be able to identify the likelihood of those moves.
but I'll give you one example
I'm sure you know what shelves are by now
yeah yeah
shell flip then the move
shell flip then the big move
right
big shell flip then the big move
you could definitely identify
you know we want to be identifying
that this shelf is weak
before the fucking highs got put in anyway
did you get it
yeah
I want to know
the shelf is weak
at that point there
because it broke
that last shelf there
you follow them
quite early on
we can anticipate the high
and from when the high is in
we can anticipate the shelf
is weak
so the response that we should get
should show
that the shelf is weak
and then once the shelf
is flipped we can anticipate
the shift
rather than having stringent
expectations to say
yeah I'm going to short it here
and write it down here
with my eyes closed
that way look you will you will have success over time
but there'll be times and periods where you take your trade
you had a bit of money on the board and you get stopped out every single time
right we want to reduce the effect of randomness
we actually want to benefit as much as we can from randomness
as much as possible so now is like
hopefully I'm setting the tone or the theme
for how and why we discuss things on social
granular detail scale
so yeah it's ridiculous
well these price behaviors are much consistent
we're just taking advantage of them